export const CHEMISTRYA2014 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The instrument used to detect the presence",
A: "cathode ray tube.",
B: "desiccator.",
C: "electron microscope.",
D: "mass spectrometer.",
answer: "D. mass spectrometer.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Neon is chemically inert because its",
A: "nuclear charge is 10.",
B: "Atomic number.",
C: "outermost shell is completely filled",
D: "nucleus contains the same number of protons and neutrons.",
answer: "C. outermost shell is completely filled",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The element with allotrope having a giant molecular structure is",
A: "carbon.",
B: "oxygen.",
C: "phosphorous.",
D: "sulphur.",
answer: "A. carbon.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The process that will cause an increase in the atomic number is the emission of",
A: "alpha particle.",
B: "beta particle.",
C: "gamma ray.",
D: "x-ray.",
answer: "B. beta particle.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Isotopes exists because atoms of the same elements may have",
A: "different number of electrons.",
B: "different number of neutrons.",
C: "the same number of protons.",
D: "the same mass number.",
answer: "B. different number of neutrons.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The number of electrons in the outermost shell of a group II element is",
A: "1",
B: "2",
C: "3",
D: "4",
answer: "B. 2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following statements does not explain why size decreases across a period?",
A: "Electrons being put into the same shell across a period",
B: "Increasing ionization energy across a period",
C: "Decreasing nuclear charge a period",
D: "Poor shielding effect of the inner shell",
answer: "C. Decreasing nuclear charge a period",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following electron configuration for an atom which has five electrons is correct?",
A: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
B: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
C: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
D: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
answer: "D.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following ions are arranged",
A: "F−, Na+,Mg2+,Al3+",
B: "Na+, Mg2+,Al3+,F−",
C: "Al3+,Na+,Mg2+,F−",
D: "Na+,Mg2+,Al3+,F−",
answer: "D. Na+, Mg2+, Al3+, F−",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Beryllium chloride has a linear structure because the hybridization of Be is",
A: "sp",
B: "sp2",
C: "sp3",
D: "sp3d",
answer: "A. sp",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The correct electron configuration of 24Cr is:",
A: "[Ar]4s13d5",
B: "[Ar]4s03d6",
C: "[Ar]4s23d4",
D: "[Ar]4s03d7",
answer: "A. [Ar]4s13d5",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The lattice energy influences the following properties in ionic compounds except",
A: "hardness.",
B: "melting point.",
C: "polarity.",
D: "solubility.",
answer: "C. polarity.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following metals has the strongest metallic bond?",
A: "Zinc",
B: "Sodium",
C: "Magnesium",
D: "Aluminium",
answer: "A. Zinc",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The number of electrons shared in the covalent bonds of methane",
A: "1",
B: "4",
C: "6",
D: "8",
answer: "D. 8",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. In which of the following reactions is the energy change referred to as electron affinity?",
A: "Na(g)−e−➔Na+(g)",
B: "Cl(g)+e−➔Cl−(g)",
C: "H+(aq)+OH−(aq)➔H2O(l)",
D: "NaCl(s)+H2O(l)➔NaCl(aq)",
answer: "B. Cl(g)+e−➔Cl−(g)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Ethanol is soluble in water because it",
A: "is covalent in nature.",
B: "contains hydrogen bond.",
C: "has low freezing point.",
D: "is an organic compound.",
answer: "B. contains hydrogen bond.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Consider the following bond representation:  This type of bond is found in",
A: "water.",
B: "calcium oxide.",
C: "ammonium chloride.",
D: "lead.",
answer: "D. lead.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The concentration of 14.63 g of salt Y in 250 cm3of solution is ……………[Y=58.5 gmol−1]",
A: "0.063 mol dm−3",
B: "30 mol dm−3",
C: "30 mol dm−3",
D: "30 mol dm−3",
answer: "D. 30 mol dm−3",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Consider the reaction represented by the following equation: Mg(s)+2HCl(aq)➔MgCl2(aq)+H2(s).  The mass of hydrogen that would be produced when 12.0 g of magnesium is completely reacted with dilute hydrochloric acid is [H 1.00, Mg= 24.0]",
A: "0.50 g",
B: "6.00 g",
C: "1.00 g",
D: "12.0g",
answer: "B. 6.00 g",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The formula of silver (I) oxide is",
A: "AgO",
B: "Ag2O",
C: "AgO2",
D: "AgO3",
answer: "B. Ag2O",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Gases are stored in liquid form under pressure so that",
A: "it can be less portable.",
B: "it can produce more energy.",
C: "larger volume could be stored.",
D: "lesser volume could be stored.",
answer: "C. larger volume could be stored.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following halogens is a solid at room temperature?",
A: "Bromine",
B: "Chlorine",
C: "Fluorine",
D: "Iodine",
answer: "D. Iodine",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The gas sample that would contain the same number of moles as 7 g of carbon (II) oxide at the same temperature and pressure is ……………[H 1.00, C= 12.0, 0= 16.0, Cl=35.5, Ar=39.9]",
A: "35.5 g of chlorine",
B: "16.0 g of oxygen",
C: "10.0 g of argon",
D: "20.0 g of hydrogen",
answer: "C. 10.0 g of argon",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following properties is responsible for the thermal and electrical conductivities of metals?",
A: "Delocalized electrons",
B: "Ductility",
C: "High density",
D: "Malleability",
answer: "A. Delocalized electrons",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The hydrolysis of NH4Cl gives",
A: "an acidic solution",
B: "an alkaline solution",
C: "a buffer solution",
D: "a neutral solution",
answer: "A. an acidic solution",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following reaction equations represents a displacement reaction?",
A: "ZnO(s)+2HCl(aq)➔ZnCl2(aq)+H2O(l)",
B: "ZnCO3(s)➔ZnO(s)+CO2(g)",
C: "Zn(s)+CuSO4(aq)➔ZnSO4(aq)+Cu(s)",
D: "ZnCl2(s)+2AgNO3(aq)➔2AgCl(aq)+Zn(NO3)2(aq)",
answer: "D. ZnCl2(s)+2AgNO3(aq)➔2AgCl(aq)+Zn(NO3)2(aq)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following pairs of substance can form a buffer solution?  \nI. CH3COOH/CH3COONa \nII. NH3/NH4Cl  \nIII. NaCl/HCl  \nIV. Na2SO4/H2SO4",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "I, III and IV only",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The pH of 0.01 mol/dm3 solution of ethanoic acid with a dissociation constant 1.8x 10−5 is",
A: "1.38",
B: "3.38",
C: "4.38",
D: "6.78",
answer: "B. 3.38",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The solubility of CaCl2 containing 120 g in 40.0 cm3 of water at 30 °C is",
A: "1.22mol/dm3",
B: "2.75mol/dm3",
C: "3.10mol/dm3",
D: "5.50mol/dm3",
answer: "B. 2.75mol/dm3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. An element that is present in proteins but not in sugar is",
A: "carbon",
B: "hydrogen",
C: "nitrogen",
D: "oxygen",
answer: "C. nitrogen",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following statements about a chemical reaction is correct?",
A: "Decrease in the amount of reactants reduces the time taken for the reaction to occur.",
B: "Increase in the amount of reactants decreases the collision rate of the particles.",
C: "The larger surface area of reactants, the faster the rate of reaction.",
D: "Increase in temperature increases the time for the reaction to occur",
answer: "C. The larger surface area of reactants, the faster the rate of reaction.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Consider the reaction represented by the following equation: N2+O2=2NO; AH =+90.3 kJ/mol  Increasing the temperature of the system would",
A: "give a lower value of K.",
B: "have no effect on the equilibrium.",
C: "shift the equilibrium position backward.",
D: "shift the equilibrium position forward.",
answer: "D. shift the equilibrium position forward.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following species is reduced in the given reaction equation? 5Fe2++MnO4−+8H+➔5Fe3++Mn2++4H2O",
A: "Fe2+",
B: "Fe3+",
C: "H+",
D: "MnO4−",
answer: "D. MnO4−",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The function of the salt bridge in an electro-chemical cell is to maintain",
A: "the concentration of the electrolyte",
B: "equilibrium system",
C: "electrical neutrality",
D: "high cell voltage",
answer: "C. electrical neutrality",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Extraction of aluminium metal is associated with the process called",
A: "crystallization.",
B: "electroplating.",
C: "electrolysis.",
D: "sublimation.",
answer: "C. electrolysis.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Consider the following diagram of the experiment set-up: The lamp would not light if X is",
A: "acidified water",
B: "chloride solution",
C: "ethanoic acid",
D: "toluene",
answer: "D. toluene",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The combustion of ethanol in excess air is represented by the following equation: C2H5OH+3O2➔2CO2+3H2O The correct representation of the bonds broken during the reaction is",
A: "C-C, C=C, C-0, C-H",
B: "C-C, 0= 0, C= 0, C-H",
C: "C-H, O =0, C-0, 0-H",
D: "C-H, C=C, 0-H, C-O",
answer: "C. C-H, O =0, C-0, 0-H",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The compound 2, 3-dimethylbut-1-ene is an isomer of",
A: "2-methylbut-2-ene",
B: "3,3-dimethylpent-1-ene",
C: "pent-1-ene",
D: "hex-1-ene",
answer: "D. hex-1-ene",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The formula (CH3)3COH represents",
A: "primary alkanol",
B: "polyhydric alkanol",
C: "secondary alkanol",
D: "tertiary alkanol",
answer: "D. tertiary alkanol",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Consider the reaction represented by the following equation: CpHq(g)+5O2➔3CO2(g)+4H2O(l).  The values of p and q are",
A: "3 and 2",
B: "3 and 4",
C: "3 and 6",
D: "3 and 8",
answer: "D. 3 and 8",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. In the production of margarine, vegetable oils are hydrogenated in the presence of nickel. This reaction",
A: "converts carbon-carbon single bonds into double bonds.",
B: "converts carbon-carbon double bonds into single bonds.",
C: "hydrolyses the oil",
D: "removes all the impurities.",
answer: "B. converts carbon-carbon double bonds into single bonds.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Metals can be stretched into wires because they are",
A: "brittle.",
B: "ductile.",
C: "elastic.",
D: "malleable.",
answer: "B. ductile.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. During the purification of bauxite, pure Al(OH)3 crystals are added to seed the Al(OH)3 in solution. The added crystals",
A: "facilitates the precipitation of Al(OH)3",
B: "increase the concentration of Al(OH)3",
C: "increase the solubility of Al(OH)3",
D: "lower the temperature of the system",
answer: "A. facilitates the precipitation of Al(OH)3",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Graphite is used as a lubricant because",
A: "it is soft.",
B: "it has a low density.",
C: "it has high melting point.",
D: "its layers slip easily over one another.",
answer: "D. its layers slip easily over one another.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The industry that uses animal skin as its major raw material is the",
A: "brewery.",
B: "soap making",
C: "tannery.",
D: "textiles.",
answer: "C. tannery.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Burning of coal containing sulphur impurity produces an air-pollutant which causes",
A: "blood poisoning.",
B: "brain damage.",
C: "corrosion of roofing sheets.",
D: "hardness of water.",
answer: "A. blood poisoning.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Which of the following materials is commonly used in the production of sculpture?",
A: "Bronze",
B: "Chromium",
C: "Duralumin",
D: "Manganese",
answer: "A. Bronze",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following carbohydrates is the least soluble in water?",
A: "Fructose",
B: "Glucose",
C: "Starch",
D: "Sucrose",
answer: "C. Starch",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. When copper and magnesium are used in alloys, they help to  \nI. hardens and strengthens the original metals  \nII. Improve the resistance to corrosion  \nIII. Improve the electrical conductance",
A: "I only",
B: "II only",
C: "I and II only",
D: "I and III",
answer: "C. I and II only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The toughness of rubber is increased by the addition of",
A: "carbon.",
B: "ethylene.",
C: "silicon.",
D: "sulphur.",
answer: "D. sulphur.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]